（ナルト）よいしょっと。
There we go.
よし。
All right!
((フカサク：蔵入り　オーケーじゃ！
Okay, storage complete!
I'm taking you back to
Hidden Leaf Village!
これから木ノ葉へ
ナルトちゃんを戻すけんの。
(そしたら　まずは
タコ探しじゃ))
After that, we'll have to
look for the octopus.
Just like Giant Gramps Sage predicted,
《デカじいちゃん仙人が
予言したとおり→
俺は　タコを探し出し→
I'm going to look for an octopus
and train to control
the Nine Tails' power.
九尾の力をコントロールできるように
修業する》
《そして　もう一度　サスケと会って》
And I'll meet Sasuke once more.
（ヤマト）それじゃ…。
Okay, let's...
（ガイ）さあ　若人よ
いざ　出発だ！
Now, young man...
Time to go!
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
The Young Man and the Sea
ああ　海だよ　海だよ！
Wow! Look, it's the sea!
Yahoo! The sea is great!
ヤッホー　海はいいな！
（アオバ）あれが
火の国　随一の港です。
That is the Land of Fire's only port.
あそこから雷の国
雲隠れへと出航します。
From there, we'll depart for
the Hidden Cloud Village
in the Land of Lightning.
なあなあ
綱手のばあちゃんが言ってた→
Say... What's this top-secret mission
that Granny Tsunade mentioned?
極秘任務って　いったい何？
秘密だから
極秘任務っていうんだよ　ナルト。
It's called a top-secret mission
because it's a secret, Naruto.
んだよ～！
そんなこと言わずにさぁ→
Oh, come on! Don't say that.
教えてくれてもいいだろ？
You can tell me.
I’ll explain later.
まっ　おいおいね。
ちぇ～！
《まだ　ナルトをごまかす
任務の内容を→
I guess he still hasn’t come up
with a cover story to fool Naruto.
思いついていないのか…》
（シズネ）綱手様　なぜ
こんな大切な時期のナルトに→
Lady Tsunade, why did you assign
Naruto on an S-rank mission
at such a critical time?
Ｓ級任務を？
Not only that, you sent him to
the Land of Lightning by sea.
しかも　海路を使って
雷の国に向かわせるなんて。
（トントン）ブヒ！
（綱手）うむ。
Yes... The Akatsuki is targeting Naruto.
ナルトは　暁に狙われている。
複雑な海路を使うことで→
I chose a difficult sea
voyage on purpose
敵に　その居場所を
悟られないことが→
in order to prevent
the enemy from finding him.
本当の目的だ。
What will Naruto be doing
雷の国　雲隠れの里で
ナルトは　どんなことを？
in Hidden Cloud Village
in the Land of Lightning?
そこは　雷影に任せてある。
I'm leaving that up to Raikage.
すっげえ！
Wow!
立派な帆船が
用意できてんじゃん！
That's a grand sailing ship
you readied for us!
いえ　我々　木ノ葉の帆船は
その隣の…。
Actually... Our Hidden Leaf ship
is the one next to it.
あちらの船なんです。
うん？
That one over there.
けぇ～　しょっぼ～。
Aw man, it looks so shabby.
極秘の任務だからね
大きい船だと目立つだろ？
It's a top-secret mission.
A big ship would attract attention, right?
こういう船で島伝いに
行ったほうがいいんだよ。
It's better to go to the island
on a boat like this.
船乗りたちの姿が
見えないようだが。
I don't see any of the seamen.
実は　外海に出ることを
嫌がってまして。
About that... They refused to set
sail into the open sea.
なに！？　お前ら→
What? Don't tell me you were
stingy on the pay?!
船乗りたちの賃金でも
ケチったのか？
No, it's not that.
いえ　そうではなく。
その…。
なんだ？
Well...
Tell me. I won't get upset.
怒らんから
ちゃんと言ってみろ。
Well, they say there is a monster
out there
この港の出口にバケモノがいて→
外海に出ようとする船を
襲うというのです。
that attacks any boat
that tries to set sail.
バケモノ？
A monster?
《あ～ぁ　貧乏クジ引いたな…》
Oh, boy... Looks like I drew
the short end of the stick.
I don't know what's going to appear,
but I'll crush it to bits!
何が出るかは知らんが→
そんなヤツ　この俺が
ギッタギタにしてやるさ！
ハッハッハッハッハー！
ガイさん
バケモノの正体もわからないのに→
I don’t know if it was a good idea for
Guy to make such a promise.
安請け合いして大丈夫かな？
We don’t even know what
kind of monster it is.
きっと　大丈夫だってばよ！
ほら！
I’m sure he’ll be fine.
See? He looks so eager
doing warm-up exercises!
あんなに元気そうに
準備運動してるし！
大丈夫ですか　ガイさん？
な　なんのこれしき…。
Are you all right, Guy?
Th-This is nothing.
船が
こんなに揺れるものとはな…。
I didn't know the boat
would sway so much.
ちょっと　胃が
驚いてしまっただけだ。
My stomach is a little shocked,
that’s all.
そんなんで
バケモノを倒せるんですか？
How can you crush a monster
in that condition?
Sure I can! I may not look it,
なに！　こう見えて
俺は　本番に強い！　うっ！
but when the time comes,
I'll be strong.
もう　外海なんですが…。
We're in open sea.
何も現れんじゃないか。
I don't see anything.
バケモノめ！
Damn monster!
Did it get scared
and run away after seeing me,
木ノ葉の燃える旋風を恐れて
逃げおったか！
the Leaf’s Burning Hurricane?
A monster!
（ガイ）バケモノ！
なんだ？　あの剣は？
Is that a sword?
口寄せ獣の一種！？
A type of Summoning Animal?
But I don’t sense any jutsu user.
しかし　術者の気配など
どこにもない。
野良の口寄せ獣だというのか？
Could it be a Wild Summoning Animal?
戻ってきたぞ！　避けろ！
It’s coming back! Avoid it!
There's not enough time!
間に合いません！
手を出すな　アオバ！
俺が止める！
Stay back, Aoba!
I'll stop it!
ガイさん！　後ろです！
なに！？
Guy, behind you!
What?!
うわぁ～っ！
♪～
I won't make it!
間に合わない！
I got you! Damn monster!
（ユウスケ）討ち取ったぜ！
このバケモノめ！
うわぁ～！
ムチャすんじゃねえぜ！
兄ちゃん！
Don't be so reckless, pal.
俺の名は　ユウスケだ。
My name is Yusuke!
海面に立つなんて
何者だ？　おめえ！
Who the hell are you and how can
you stand on the ocean surface?!
I'm Naruto, a ninja from
the Hidden Leaf.
俺は　木ノ葉の忍　うずまきナルト！
あとは　俺に任せとけ！
Leave the rest to me!
ん？　あっ！　印が組めねえ！
I can't weave
my signs like this!
えぇ～っ！！
木遁　大樹林の術！
Wood Style: Giant Forest!
♪～
You have to undo your jutsu
or you'll be drawn in!
術を解かねえと
引き込まれちまう！
Quickly, take him and go!
早く！
その人と逃げるんだ！
散千烏の術！
Scattering Crow Jutsu!
♪～
BIG CATCH
Why would there be
a Summoning Animal in a spot like that?
口寄せ獣が→
なんで　あんなところに
いるんだってばよ？
Maybe it survived
the Third Great Ninja War?
第三次忍界大戦の
生き残りじゃないだろうか。
No wonder the seamen are scared.
あれでは船乗りたちが恐れるのも
無理ないね。
アイツは　１５年程前から→
That thing's been living there
for about 15 years.
あそこに　棲みついてやがる。
やはり。
I see.
Normally, when the ninja who
is contracted with it dies,
普通　契約した忍が死ぬと
自分の世界へ戻るものだが。
the animal returns to its own world.
But why is that one acting up like that?
けど　アイツってば
なんで暴れてるんだ？
あの口寄せ獣のなかでは→
Maybe the war has not ended
for that Summoning Animal.
まだ戦いが続いているのかも
しれない。
えぇ。
Yeah.
フンッ　忍同士の戦いなんて
迷惑だぜ。
Your ninja wars are such a nuisance!
Because of that thing,
アイツのせいで
腰抜け船乗りどもは→
all the cowardly seamen refuse
to go to sea anymore!
誰も外海に
出なくなっちまった。
Cowardly?
腰抜けって…。
What were you thinking,
doing something so dangerous?!
あんな危ないことして
兄ちゃん　何　考えてんだよ。
A fisherman's job is to catch fish.
魚を獲るのが
漁師の仕事だからな。
I thought I was gonna get rid
of him once and for all,
今日という今日は　アイツにトドメを
刺そうと思ってたのに→
only to have you interfere!
邪魔しやがってよ。
If I hadn't saved you,
you'd be fish food about now.
俺が助けなきゃ
今頃　アイツのエサだろうが。
フンッ。
You should just leave
that thing to us
アイツは俺たちに任せろ。
and stop acting so recklessly.
もうムチャなことは　やめろってばよ。
Shut up.
うるせぇな！
アイツを倒すのは　このユウスケ様だ。
If anyone beats that thing,
it's gonna be me, Yusuke!
I’m not asking for much.
贅沢は言わねえ。
If I only had a sturdier boat
俺に　あのカジキの体当たりに
負けない→
that could withstand that
marlin's body blows.
もう少し頑丈な船がありゃ。
And an internal-combustion engine
to match that marlin's power.
それに　カジキのパワーに負けねえ
内燃機関がのせてありゃ。
And maybe a fishing rod that
has a lure and won't snap.
あとは　大物を釣っても折れねえ
ルアー用の釣り竿がありゃ。
That's asking for quite a lot.
って　十分　贅沢だろ。
フンッ。
Tell me.
なぁ　どうして　あのカジキに
そこまで　こだわるんだ？
How come you're so determined
to get that marlin?
親父さんか？
Is that your dad?
We're dead serious about
fighting that fish.
俺たちは
魚とガチで勝負してんだよ。
A guy who'd lose...
その勝負に
負けちまうようなヤツは→
isn't worth being called
a father or a son!
親でもなけりゃ　子でもねえ！
Captain Yamato,
isn't there anything we can do?
ヤマト隊長
なんとかなんねえのかな。
Like what?
なんとかって？
Like lending him a hand.
だから　俺たちで
手助けしてやることできねえかな。
I want Yusuke to avenge his dad.
っつうか　ユウスケ兄ちゃんに→
仇を討たせて
やりてぇんだってばよ。
But you have an S-rank mission...
しかし　キミにはＳ級任務が…。
うぉ～っ！
I’ve been moved to tears, Yamato!
俺は　猛烈に感動したぞ　ヤマト！
Let’s give him a helping hand!
Come on, do it! I’ll do it too!
ここは　ひと肌　脱ごうじゃないか。
お前も脱げ　俺も脱ぐぞ！
Well, as long as that monster
is there, we can't set sail.
確かに
あのオバケカジキがいるかぎり→
出航できないしな。
You see!
だよな！
あのカジキが口寄せ獣だとしたら→
If that marlin is
a Summoning Animal,
then we shinobi are to blame
for Yusuke's misfortune.
俺たち忍が　ユウスケ兄ちゃんに
迷惑をかけたことになるし。
And it's not like that marlin
is here because it wants to be.
それに　あのカジキだって→
好きでこの海に
いるわけじゃない。
Okay, okay. I understand.
わかりましたよ　もう。
All right!
よ～し！
BIG CATCH
Yusuke!
ユウスケ兄ちゃん！
We have a fishing rod too!
竿もあるってばよ！
ナルト…。
Naruto...
What do you think?
どうでしょう？
I tried making them
with the data I had available.
資料をもとに
作ってみたんですが。
I have no quarrel with
the boat or the rod.
船も竿も申し分ねえが→
But this is not a motorized boat.
こいつは　手漕ぎ。
Without an internal combustion engine
that can match the marlin's power,
カジキのパワーに負けない
内燃機関がついてねえとムリだ。
it's useless.
You can leave that to me!
それは　この俺に任せておけ。
When it comes to power,
パワーだけなら
この気高き碧い猛獣　マイト・ガイ→
no one can compete with I,
Might Guy, the Noble Blue Beast!
誰にも負けやしない。
So what do you say?
どうだってばよ？
フンッ
余計なことばっかしやがって。
Can't you mind your own business?
With all this, you're taking
the thrill out of the fight.
こんなに用意されちゃ→
アイツとの勝負の醍醐味が
なくなっちまうだろうが。
Well, aren’t you stubborn?
かぁ…　素直じゃねえな。
Giant marlin spotted 30 degrees
to the right!
右前方３０度に　巨大カジキ発見。
Hey, go around in front of him!
おい　ヤツの前方に　まわってくれ。
You got it!
よし　任せておけ！
エイヤッサッサ　エイヤッサ！
We're up front!
前に出たってばよ。
Okay, I'm going to release the lure.
よし　ルアーを流すぞ。
Hey, what is that?!
って　何だ　これ！？
It's a special lure made in proportion
to its huge size.
ヤツの巨体に合わせた　特製ルアーだ。
I meant, why does it look
just like me?
そうじゃなくて…
何で俺そっくり？
You're showy and look like
you'd be good bait.
お前は派手で
食いつきがよさそうだからな。
No! I'm gonna get eaten!
いや～　俺が食われる！
Faster!
もっと速く！
We have to make it think
this lure is nice and fresh!
ヤツに　ルアーが生きのいいエサだと
思わせねえと。
Leave it to me!
任せろ
八門遁甲　第二休門　開！
Eight Inner Gates!
Second Gate, Gate of Rest! Open!
Bushy Brow Sensei! Faster!
ゲキマユ先生　もっとだ！
Fourth Gate, Gate of Pain...
Fifth Gate, Gate of Closing...
第四傷門　第五杜門　開！
Open!
Come on, come on, come on!
こい　こい　こい！
おっ！
ヒット！
Bull's-eye!
He took the bait!
アイツ　まんまと
かぶりつきやがった。
えっ！？
なんか　心が痛い…。
Oh, that hurts my heart.
Say, we have to reel it in quickly.
なあ　早く
引っ張りあげねえのか？
You idiot. If we did that,
the line would snap.
バカ野郎　そんなことしたら
糸がもたねえ。
We'll let it play
and wait until it tires out.
遊ばせて　ヤツが疲れるのを待つ。
We'll run out of line like this!
このままじゃ
糸がなくなっちまうぞ。
I know that.
わかってる
この船ごと引かせる。
Let it pull the boat!
Can you keep up with it?
ヤツについていけるか？
Nothing is impossible for me!
この俺に不可能はない！
うおぉ～！！
You don't need to row anymore.
もう漕がなくていい。
Just follow the marlin’s lead
and steer the boat.
ヤツの動きに合わせて
舵をきってくれ。
Good. I was reaching my limit.
ふぅ　助かった
さすがに　もう　限界だった。
Swim, swim...
Use up all your strength.
泳げ　泳げ！
力を使い切るんだ。
It's got amazing stamina
to swim at this speed.
これほどのスピードで泳ぎ続けるとは
相当なスタミナだ。
But it will eventually use up
the energy to resist.
だが　振りきろうとする力も
いつか尽きる。
Then the real fight begins.
そこからが勝負でしょう。
It's finally showing signs of exhaustion.
ヤツめ　やっと疲れが見えてきたぜ。
くっ！
ユウスケ兄ちゃん！
Yusuke!
Stay out of my way!
邪魔すんじゃねえ！
これは　俺とアイツのガチファイティングだ。
This fight is between him and me!
I know that!
わかってるってばよ。
Here we go.
《もうすぐだ　今度こそ…。
This time... This time for sure.
今度こそ　ヤツを！》
Guess it’s time to help out.
そろそろ助けがいるかな。
Don't help him!
手出しちゃダメだ。
Yusuke will get his revenge
with his own two hands.
ユウスケ兄ちゃんに　自分の手で
仇を討ってもらうんだ。
Oh dear...
やれやれ。
任せるしかないみたいだね。
I guess we have no choice.
All right, just a little more!
よし　もうちょっと！
Give it up already!
観念しやがれ！
He still has so much strength.
こいつ　まだ　こんな力が！
くっ！
This isn't good!
まずい！
Yusuke!
兄ちゃん！
この～っ！
♪～
You avenged your dad.
親父さんの仇　討てたってばよ。
ああ！
Yeah!
Why didn't that Summoning Animal
return to its birthplace?
あの口寄せ獣　なぜ
生まれ故郷に戻らなかったのか。
Easy there. I'll get it out.
我慢しろ　今　抜いてやる。
This is...
これ…。
It's a Demon Wind Shuriken
from the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉の風魔手裏剣だな。
So it was a victim of
the Third Great Ninja War, after all.
やっぱり　あのカジキも→
第三次忍界大戦の
犠牲者だったんだな。
If possible, we'd like to return it
to its birthplace.
生まれ故郷に
戻してやりたいんだが。
Sure, do whatever you like with it.
ああ　好きにしろ。
Our one-on-one duel is over.
一対一の真剣勝負は
もう終わった。
No more grudges.
恨みっこなしだ。
♪～
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokyuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
dance dance dance to you
just just just to you
akai itode tsunagacchattenda
We're connected by the Red String of Fate
dareka ga dareka wo damashite achichi
Somebody is doing something
burning hot by deceiving somebody
sonna de iinoka?
Are you OK with that?
ore wa chigauze baka ni sunjanee
I'm not like them. You don't know the first thing about me
kitanai kirei giragira no sora
The dirty, beautiful sky glitters
antanimo mieterunokai?
Can you see it too?
hageshiku aishi aisareta koto wa arunokai?
Have you ever loved, and been loved, passionately?
ore to anta no kizuna wa dounatterundai?
What's become of our bond?
c'mon!
haato dokyun de bachibachi sunzen
My heart is thumping and about to explode
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! aini mudawanee!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Love is it!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Next Episode
I can’t take it anymore! Get me off this ship!
Get a hold of yourself, Bushy Brow Sensei!
（くもじい）
もしもし　そこのあなた。
But these waves are indeed hard to take!
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのは　どうじゃろう？
Then what are we going to do?
Get me off! Get me off, please!
今回は　渋谷発展の歴史スペシャルじゃ。
（くもみ）渋谷？
It’s going to be off course,
but there should be an island up ahead.
That’s it. Let’s stop there! Set sail towards north-northeast!
なぜ渋谷が流行の発信地に
なったのか。
えっ　理由があるんですか？
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: “The Ninja of Benisu”
あの１０９も昔は…。
The Ninja of Benisu
Naruto? What are you doing here?
小さなお店がぎっしり！
そして　渋谷の未来も見ていくぞ。
おぉ～！